consumersmokingsurveys.com 2009-03-02

# ConsumerSmokingSurveys.com

## Effective Date: January 1, 2007

This privacy statement covers the website ConsumerSmokingSurveys. If you have questions or concerns regarding this notice, you should first contact us by email at [privacy@ConsumerSmokingSurveys.com](mailto:privacy@ConsumerSmokingSurveys.com) or by postal at ConsumerSmokingSurveys, 655 Deerfield Rd. #100-193 deerfield, ILLINOIS 60015.

ConsumerSmokingSurveys is a media property owned by ConsumerSmokingSurveys, LLC, a leading online marketing company. ConsumerSmokingSurveys, LLC, ("We," "Us," "Our," "ConsumerSmokingSurveys"), understands how important privacy is to our members ("you," "your"]. We have created this online Privacy Policy to let you know what information is being collected on our websites, how the information is being used and what choices you have regarding the collection and use of the information. Please take a moment to review this policy and feel free to contact us with any questions at [privacy@ConsumerSmokingSurveys.com](mailto:privacy@ConsumerSmokingSurveys.com).

## WHAT INFORMATION IS COLLECTED?

Generally, We gather two types of information. The first type of information is the Personally Identifiable Information ("Personal Information") that you expressly provide when you enroll via the online registration forms on our website. This Personal Information includes but is not limited to your name, mailing address, email address, date of birth, gender and telephone.

In addition to the Personal Information you provide to Us, We will also collect certain information online and offline arising out of your use of ConsumerSmokingSurveys, including but not limited to the number and type of offers you have responded to and completed.

## HOW DO WE USE THE INFORMATION COLLECTED?

We use your email address to notify you of program updates, special offers and promotions. We use the Personal Information you provide to service your program. For example, We request your mailing address so We know where to send your benefits that you may receive as part of the program, and any other information you may request. We also may use this information to notify you via email, postal mail or phone about new products or services and special promotions as well as to tailor our partners' marketing offers that We display to you throughout ConsumerSmokingSurveys and within email communications.

ConsumerSmokingSurveys distributes offers for the purchase of subscriptions and merchandise from our partners, which include national retailers, online merchants, credit card companies and service providers. If you elect to purchase or apply for a subscription or merchandise through ConsumerSmokingSurveys from one of our partners, the order form requests information that may include contact information (such as name, address, phone number, and email address) as well as financial information (such as credit card number). Certain offers that appear on our website may require that you provide financial information to Us so that we can, in turn, provide it to our partner who is sponsoring that offer. This partner-requested information will only be provided to the specific sponsor of that offer, and only if you submit that offer. ConsumerSmokingSurveys will not use this information.

ConsumerSmokingSurveys may choose to provide aggregate non-personally identifiable demographic information about you to non-affiliated third-parties for statistical purposes only.

We reserve the right to send you certain transactional messages relating to the ConsumerSmokingSurveys service, such as service announcements, administrative messages, etc., that are considered part of your ConsumerSmokingSurveys account, without offering you the opportunity to opt-out of receiving them.

## MARKETING PARTNERS

We may use the Personal Information that you supply to Us and We may share this information with other third party businesses that may have no relationship to ConsumerSmokingSurveys, in order to bring you special retail opportunities through direct mail, email and telemarketing.

From time to time, We may share your name, address, phone or email address with nonaffiliated partners and/or affiliated third parties who offer products or services that We feel may be of interest to you. Affiliated companies are those companies that control, are controlled by, or are under common control with another company. ConsumerSmokingSurveys, LLC may also send you emails on behalf of our partners.

Some offers or services will require Us, by their terms, to forward your personal information (such as mailing address for delivery of orders) to a partner so that they can provide the service directly to you. If you become a Member through a partner web site, your basic enrollment, activity and interest information may be shared with that partner, as applicable, and that partner may share information it collects about you with Us, subject to its own information practices and privacy policies. We share this information so that we can credit your account for the points earned with that offer. We will provide you with notice of such instances at the point where the information is collected. The choice to participate is yours.

## SERVICE PROVIDERS

In order to provide the products or services you have requested, We may disclose the information We collect to companies that perform services on our behalf, such as the credit reporting agencies from which we obtain your credit report(s), credit card processors, email communications management firms or call center providers. Our third- party service providers are contractually limited to using the information received from ConsumerSmokingSurveys solely for the purposes of providing you with the services you requested.

In addition to the Personal Information you provide to Us, We will also collect certain information online and offline arising out of your use of ConsumerSmokingSurveys, including but not limited to the number and type of offers you have responded to and completed.

## WHAT IS THE UNSUBSCRIBE PROCESS?

ConsumerSmokingSurveys Offers  
We use your email address to notify you of program updates, special offers and promotions. You may select at any time to opt-out of receiving emailed marketing offers from Us, our partners and/or our affiliated companies using the "Unsubscribe" link at the bottom any future email you receive from Us.

Non-affiliated 3rd Parties  
If you prefer not to receive email offers from our non-affiliated third parties, you may click the "Unsubscribe" link available on the bottom of each email you receive from a non-affiliated third party, and follow the instructions on the screen.

Please note that suppressed contact information will not be used for any other purpose other than to ensure compliance with your opt-out request, in response to inquiries by law enforcement and to comply with any other applicable state and/or federal laws regarding your choices for commercial email marketing, such as the Controlling the Assault of Non-Solicited Pornography and Marketing Act of 2003 (CAN-SPAM).

## WHAT ARE COOKIES AND HOW DO WE USE THEM?

ConsumerSmokingSurveys uses a feature of your Internet browser called a "cookie" to assign a unique identification to your computer. Cookies are files that your Web browser places on your computer's hard drive. Cookies can be used to help save and retrieve passwords used on ConsumerSmokingSurveys and to save information on past activities and other preferences. That way, you don't have to re-enter information every time you visit ConsumerSmokingSurveys. When you visit ConsumerSmokingSurveys, We read the cookie to help target and personalize offers to you. For example, the cookie can help ensure that you don't see an offer that you have already completed. Cookies also let ConsumerSmokingSurveys know if We have repeat visitors. We also use cookies to identify which sites our repeat visitors are coming from. ConsumerSmokingSurveys does not and cannot use cookies to retrieve personal information about you from your computer unless such information was knowingly and willingly provided by you. ConsumerSmokingSurveys respects your privacy and ConsumerSmokingSurveys cookies are not linked to any personally identifiable information. ConsumerSmokingSurveys works with third parties to serve ads on our websites. These ads may contain cookies and/or action tags (also known as single pixel gifs) to measure advertising effectiveness and gather completely anonymous information. We have no access to or control over these cookies or action tags.

You are always free to decline these cookies if your browser permits, however, you may not be able to use certain features on ConsumerSmokingSurveys and you may be asked to re-enter your password more frequently during your session.

## HOW DO WE PROTECT PERSONAL INFORMATION?

We have security measures in place designed to protect the security of your information. When you submit your credit card information, the 128-bit encrypted Secure Socket Layer (SSL) connection scrambles or encrypts your information before it is sent to Us over the Internet. This protects your credit card information from being read while it is transferred. SSL is supported by Netscape 2.0+, Microsoft IE 3.0+ and most frame-enabled browsers. Depending on which browser you use, you will know you are in a secured area by "https" or a small key or padlock in the bottom right corner of your browser indicating that your transaction is secure.

## DO THESE SAME PRIVACY POLICIES APPLY TO THIRD PARTY WEBSITES THAT YOU ACCESS THROUGH ConsumerSmokingSurveys?

No. The Privacy Policy appearing on ConsumerSmokingSurveys relates only to ConsumerSmokingSurveys. You will notice that our website may contain links to other sites, such as our partners. We cannot be responsible for the privacy and security practices of other websites that you may access through ConsumerSmokingSurveys, even if displayed within a frame on our site. You should always review a particular site's privacy and security policies when linking to that site before revealing any personal information to that site.

## PRIVACY POLICY CHANGES

We reserve the right to change this Privacy Policy at any time. You agree to obtain changes to this Privacy Policy electronically by visiting this Site. We require you to check back from time to time to review changes to our Privacy Policy.

## TRANSFERABILITY OF PERSONAL INFORMATION

In the event We go through a business transition, such as a merger, acquisition by another company, or sale of all or a portion of our assets, your Personal Information will likely be among the assets transferred. You will be notified by means of notice on [our Sites] for thirty (30) days prior to any such change in ownership or control of your Personal Information. For more information, please refer to the section labeled "Privacy Policy Changes," above.

## A SPECIAL NOTE REGARDING PEOPLE UNDER THE AGE OF 18 YEARS OLD

Consumers under the age of 18 must not send any personal information to Us-including but not limited to their name, address or email address.

## HOW TO CONTACT US

If you have any questions about the practices of the ConsumerSmokingSurveys  you can contact Us by visiting the Contact Us section of this website, or via postal mail at ConsumerSmokingSurveys, 655 Deerfield Rd. #100-193 deerfield, ILLINOIS 60015.
